<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Forensics on MMOX</title>
    <link>https://mmox.me/tags/digital-forensics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Forensics on MMOX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmox.me/tags/digital-forensics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Defend - vLP</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/letsdefend/vlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/letsdefend/vlp/</guid>
      <description>Description Our friend fell victim to a suspicious crack tool. but it seems it didn&amp;#39;t goes in the right path so investigate it to find any evidence. Tools Tools Required 1- Volatility 2- Notepad++ 3- VirusTotal or VM. 4- Linux Command Line Writeup Q1 How many users are on the machine? In this question we can use filescan then grep the Users and sort them and find the uniq
python3 /mnt/d/volatility3/vol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Defenders - Sysinternals</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/sysinternals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/sysinternals/</guid>
      <description>Description A user thought they were downloading the SysInternals tool suite and attempted to open it, but the tools did not launch and became inaccessible. Since then, the user has observed that their system has gradually slowed down and become less responsive.Challenge Link : https://cyberdefenders.org/blueteam-ctf-challenges/55Supportive Tools:
Registry Explorer Event Log Explorer AppCompatCachParser VirsuTotal Web Cache View FTK Imager Autopsy Writeup Q1 1: What was the malicious executable file name that the user downloaded?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Defenders - Patrick</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/patrick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/patrick/</guid>
      <description>Description This image was captured from an iPhone of a user who likes to play video games, especially Minecraft, and communicates with friends. But is this user doing something they shouldn&#39;t be?. We need to identify any kind of anomaly behavior done by this user.Challenge Link : https://cyberdefenders.org/blueteam-ctf-challenges/96Supportive Tools:
CyberChef iLEAPP dcode DB Browser for SQLite unfurl MacForensics PList Deserializer Writeup Q1 1: Personal List! -&amp;gt; How many items were on Patrick&#39;s shopping list?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Defenders - XLM-Macros</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/xlm-macros/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/xlm-macros/</guid>
      <description>Description Recently, we have seen a resurgence of Excel-based malicous office documents. Howerver, instead of using VBA-style macros, they are using older style Excel 4 macros. This changes our approach to analyzing these documents, requiring a slightly different set of tools. In this challenge, you&#39;ll get hands-on with two documents that use Excel 4.0 macros to perform anti-analysis and download the next stage of the attack.Challenge Link : https://cyberdefenders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CyCTF 2022 Writeups</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/cyctf2022-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/cyctf2022-writeup/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Name Challenge link Type Lazaretto ✔ Download Forensics Hotel ✔ Download Forensics Subscription Download Forensics Geology docker pull cyctf/geology Forensics imPOSTer ✔ Download Forensics Mach ✔ Download Mobile Lazaretto Challege Description Writeup we were provided with an ad1 file using FTKimager we were able to open it and it had only windows event logs
So i just dumped the files and using the famous ericzimmerman tool EvtxECmd i was able to pares the full events into a csv file using this command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Defenders - AzurePot</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/azurepot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/azurepot/</guid>
      <description>Description This Ubuntu Linux honeypot was put online in Azure in early October to watch what happens with those exploiting CVE-2021-41773.Initially, there was a large number of crypto miners that hit the system. You will see one cron script meant to remove files named kinsing in /tmp. This was a way of preventing these miners so more interesting things could occur. Challenge Files: sdb.vhd.gz VHD of the main drive obtained through an Azure disk snapshot ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Defenders - Ulysses</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/ulysses-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/ulysses-writeup/</guid>
      <description>Description A Linux server was possibly compromised and a forensic analysis is required in order to understand what really happened. Hard disk dumps and memory snapshots of the machine are provided in order to solve the challenge.
Challenge Files: victoria-v8.kcore.img: memory dump done by dd’ing /proc/kcore. victoria-v8.memdump.img: memory dump done with memdump. Debian5_26.zip: volatility custom Linux profile. Challenge Link : https://cyberdefenders.org/labs/41Supportive Tools: Volatilty 2.6 FTK imger HxD Writeup Q1 The attacker was performing a Brute Force attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryuk Ransomware Analysis Memory Detection - Part 1 </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/dfir/ryuk-analysis-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/dfir/ryuk-analysis-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Ryuk is a ransomware which encrypts its victim&amp;rsquo;s files and asks for a ransom via bitcoin to release the original files. It is has been observed being used to attack companies or professional environments. Cybersecurity experts figured out that Ryuk and Hermes ransomware shares pieces of codes. Hermes is commodity ransomware that has been observed for sale on dark-net forums and used by multiple threat actors.
And I am going to do some analysis form a forensics perspective</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Defenders - BankingTroubles</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/bankingtroubles-memory-image-forensics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/bankingtroubles-memory-image-forensics/</guid>
      <description>Description Company X has contacted you to perform forensics work on a recent incident that occurred. One of their employees had received an e-mail from a co-worker that pointed to a PDF file. Upon opening, the employee did not notice anything; however, they recently had unusual activity in their bank account.The initial theory is that a user received an e-mail, containing an URL leading to a forged PDF document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MemLabs Writeup - Lab 1 (Beginner&#39;s Luck - Easy) </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab1/</guid>
      <description>Lab Challenge link difficulty Writeup link Lab 1 Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Luck Easy Lab 1 Lab 2 A New World Easy Lab 2 Lab 3 The Evil&amp;rsquo;s Den Easy - Medium Lab 3 Lab 4 Obsession Medium Lab 4 Lab 5 Black Tuesday Medium - Hard Lab 5 Lab 6 The Reckoning Hard Lab 6 Challenge description My sister&#39;s computer crashed. We were very fortunate to recover this memory dump. Your job is get all her important files from the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MemLabs Writeup - Lab 1 (Beginner&#39;s Luck - Easy) </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/root-me-forensics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/root-me-forensics/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Link difficulty Lab 1 Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Luck Easy Lab 2 A New World Easy Lab 3 The Evil&amp;rsquo;s Den Easy - Medium Lab 4 Obsession Medium Lab 5 Black Tuesday Medium - Hard Lab 6 The Reckoning Hard Challenge description Congratulations Berthier, thanks to your help the computer has been identified. You have requested a memory dump but before starting your analysis you wanted to take a look at the antivirus’ logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MemLabs Writeup - Lab 2 (A New World - Easy) </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab2/</guid>
      <description>Lab Challenge link difficulty Writeup link Lab 1 Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Luck Easy Lab 1 Lab 2 A New World Easy Lab 2 Lab 3 The Evil&amp;rsquo;s Den Easy - Medium Lab 3 Lab 4 Obsession Medium Lab 4 Lab 5 Black Tuesday Medium - Hard Lab 5 Lab 6 The Reckoning Hard Lab 6 Challenge description One of the clients of our company, lost the access to his system due to an unknown error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MemLabs Writeup - Lab 3 (The Evil&#39;s Den - Easy Medium) </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab3/</guid>
      <description>Lab Challenge link difficulty Writeup link Lab 1 Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Luck Easy Lab 1 Lab 2 A New World Easy Lab 2 Lab 3 The Evil&amp;rsquo;s Den Easy - Medium Lab 3 Lab 4 Obsession Medium Lab 4 Lab 5 Black Tuesday Medium - Hard Lab 5 Lab 6 The Reckoning Hard Lab 6 Challenge description A malicious script encrypted a very secret piece of information I had on my system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MemLabs Writeup - Lab 4 (Obsession - Medium) </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab4/</guid>
      <description>Lab Challenge link difficulty Writeup link Lab 1 Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Luck Easy Lab 1 Lab 2 A New World Easy Lab 2 Lab 3 The Evil&amp;rsquo;s Den Easy - Medium Lab 3 Lab 4 Obsession Medium Lab 4 Lab 5 Black Tuesday Medium - Hard Lab 5 Lab 6 The Reckoning Hard Lab 6 Challenge description My system was recently compromised. The Hacker stole a lot of information but he also deleted a veryimportant file of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MemLabs Writeup - Lab 5 (Black Tuesday - Medium Hard) </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab5/</guid>
      <description>Lab Challenge link difficulty Writeup link Lab 1 Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Luck Easy Lab 1 Lab 2 A New World Easy Lab 2 Lab 3 The Evil&amp;rsquo;s Den Easy - Medium Lab 3 Lab 4 Obsession Medium Lab 4 Lab 5 Black Tuesday Medium - Hard Lab 5 Lab 6 The Reckoning Hard Lab 6 Challenge description We received this memory dump from our client recently. Someone accessed his system when he was notthere and he found some rather strange files being accessed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MemLabs Writeup - Lab 6 (The Reckoning - Hard) </title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/memlabs-lab6/</guid>
      <description>Lab Challenge link difficulty Writeup link Lab 1 Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Luck Easy Lab 1 Lab 2 A New World Easy Lab 2 Lab 3 The Evil&amp;rsquo;s Den Easy - Medium Lab 3 Lab 4 Obsession Medium Lab 4 Lab 5 Black Tuesday Medium - Hard Lab 5 Lab 6 The Reckoning Hard Lab 6 Challenge description We received this memory dump from the Intelligence Bureau Department. They say this evidencemight hold some secrets of the underworld gangster David Benjamin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wicsme 2020 Writeups</title>
      <link>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/wicsme2020-writeups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmox.me/posts/writeups/wicsme2020-writeups/</guid>
      <description>Digital Forensics Fe01 It was an easy one there was a .rtf file when i opened it using (&amp;ldquo;libre office Writer&amp;rdquo;) i found:
by clicking (Ctr+A) I selected all the right clicked to choose paragraph - Text Body
the flag appered the flag was : n𝑖𝐶𝑒𝐴𝑛𝐷𝐸𝑎𝑠𝑦10018
Fe02 it was a PDF File with a black mark that hide some parts of the text, I Opend it using (&amp;ldquo;Atril Document Viewer&amp;rdquo;) And that what appered:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
